<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 15:32:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Windows Defender on Windows Server 2019</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/defender-on-windows-server-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/defender-on-windows-server-2019/</guid><description>Error message: You&amp;rsquo;ll need a new app to open this windowsdefender</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security &amp; Responsibility</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 06:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</guid><description>After seeing that some of us - if not most of us - is still able to mess up the configuration of the cloud hosted resources and therefor open up the possibility of some information disclosures, I thought that we need an updated diagram about our responsibilities.
Updated Cloud Security Responsibility Model
The yellow items are my addition, and they show where most of the challenges are located. For a &amp;ldquo;capability team&amp;rdquo; which never had to deal with virtual networks and access management of the resources before the cloud era, I believe these are the parts of the cloud where most of the learning is needed, and could have an epic failure.</description></item><item><title>Practical guide to manage the PAW machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:22:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</guid><description>Where we are We already have some quality materials - like the Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architecture - about the security best practices of the Azure Cloud including possibly everything related to Cybersecurity but I feel that something is missing and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why in a moment.
Reference Architecture
If you take a closer look at the reference material you&amp;rsquo;ll see a red bar with the text: Privileged Admin Workstations (PAWs) and in the right side of that bar you&amp;rsquo;ll see ESAE Admin Forest which is described here ESAE Administrative Forest Design Approach</description></item><item><title>Red Team type of Access to Azure from Anywhere</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</guid><description>! Warning ! The content of this post might not be aligned with you company&amp;rsquo;s internal IT security rules, I suggest to talk to your manager and request an approval before you try this out in any of your environments.
Introduction, setting the stage We should start with an overall picture of an imaginary Enterprise network
Imagine that your ADFS is sitting behind the corporate firewall and your users cannot access it from the Internet without VPN.</description></item><item><title>How do I vet the third party applications</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 20:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</guid><description>There are lots of third party software vendors focusing on applications and services to extend the functionality of Office 365. There is even a marketplace called AppSource where you can shop from these apps and services.
AppSource
There are hundreds of applications in each category from where you just have to pick those you like and add them to Office 365 but bare in mind that these apps will ask for permissions in the same way how apps are asking for permissions on your mobile device.</description></item><item><title>Adding Users to Local Groups</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/adding-users-to-local-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/adding-users-to-local-groups/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the new SharePoint Server 2019 in the last couple of days and after I joined my new VM to the Domain I needed to add my SP_SETUP account to the local Administrators group but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to log in with my Domain Admin to the server.
In the past we had to use the [ADSI] type accelerator to add a local or domain user to a Local Group.</description></item></channel></rss>