<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Compliance on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/tags/compliance/</link><description>Recent content in Compliance on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 22:24:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/tags/compliance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Microsoft Azure Compliance Manager</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</guid><description>As you probably know Microsoft has a Service Trust Portal from where you can get the #Compliance related information for all Microsoft cloud cervices.
You can even download the Security and Compliance Blueprints
Compliance Manager One of the most helpful offering of the Service Trust Portal is the Compliance Manager, a workflow-based risk assessment tool in which you can get a good overview of your Compliance score which will reflect on how Microsoft understood the different regulations/certifications and the controls required to meet the requirements of these.</description></item><item><title>How do I vet the third party applications</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 20:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</guid><description>There are lots of third party software vendors focusing on applications and services to extend the functionality of Office 365. There is even a marketplace called AppSource where you can shop from these apps and services.
There are hundreds of applications in each category from where you just have to pick those you like and add them to Office 365 but bare in mind that these apps will ask for permissions in the same way how apps are asking for permissions on your mobile device.</description></item></channel></rss>