<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Admin on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/tags/admin/</link><description>Recent content in Admin on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 10:29:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/tags/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to manage Hyper-V Administrators on Azure AD joined machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/manage-local-groups-on-azure-ad-joined-machines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 10:29:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/manage-local-groups-on-azure-ad-joined-machines/</guid><description>Get-VM : You do not have the required permission to complete this task. Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that using Add-LocalGroupMember on our Azure AD joined device.</description></item><item><title>Admin Guide for your Free Microsoft Teams Subscription (Updated)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-admin-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-admin-guide/</guid><description>Microsoft Teams - The Admin&amp;rsquo;s Check List What do you want to do is to make sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the following checklist:
You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to create additional Global Admin accounts. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to turn on the Multi-Factor Authentication for the Admin accounts. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to change the default technical contact to a distribution group. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to update the Privacy Contact information.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security &amp; Responsibility</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 06:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</guid><description>After seeing that some of us - if not most of us - is still able to mess up the configuration of the cloud hosted resources and therefor open up the possibility of some information disclosures, I thought that we need an updated diagram about our responsibilities.
Updated Cloud Security Responsibility Model
The yellow items are my addition, and they show where most of the challenges are located.</description></item><item><title>Practical guide to manage the PAW machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:22:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</guid><description>Where we are We already have some quality materials - like the Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architecture - about the security best practices of the Azure Cloud including possibly everything related to Cybersecurity but I feel that something is missing and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why in a moment. If you take a closer look at the reference material you&amp;rsquo;ll see a red bartitled: Privileged Admin Workstations (PAWs) and in the right side of that bar you&amp;rsquo;ll see ESAE Admin Forest which is described here ESAE Administrative Forest Design Approach</description></item><item><title>Whiteboard PowerShell</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/whiteboard-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/whiteboard-powershell/</guid><description>People leave the organization. They might retire or look for bigger challenges. Either way as an Office 365 Administrator you have to deal with the situation.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy with SharePoint or with Exchange because they are older services, well documented and you probably have experience with them. So you know how to change ownership of a Site Collection or a Mailbox.
But that is not the case with the Whiteboard Service.</description></item></channel></rss>