<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 19:10:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skype for Business is gone (part 1)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/s4bo-p1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 19:10:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/s4bo-p1/</guid><description>Skype for Business Online is gone now and left a gap while Microsoft Teams might be too much to fill said gap. Have a look!</description></item><item><title>Wrapping snap-ins into modules</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/wrapping-snap-ins-into-modules/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 12:04:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/wrapping-snap-ins-into-modules/</guid><description>Windows PowerShell snap-ins wrapped into modules will give us module auto-loading for the snap-ins.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition Preview</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-se-preview-features/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:57:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-se-preview-features/</guid><description>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition Preview, list of features, and feature IDs.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server új napra ébredt</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/hun-sharepoint-server-se/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 18:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/hun-sharepoint-server-se/</guid><description>Itt az új SharePoint Server Subscription Edition előzetes kiadása</description></item><item><title>Rolling logs with PowerShell</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/rolling-logs-with-powershell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 12:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/rolling-logs-with-powershell/</guid><description>Rolling logs will help you understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening in your script, live.</description></item><item><title>Install Modules for both PowerShell editions</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/module-for-all/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 13:58:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/module-for-all/</guid><description>Install a PowerShell module on Windows once and use it with both Windows PowerShell and PowerShell (core)</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Graph PowerShell SDK for Azure AD - Part 1</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/mggraph-azuread-part1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 05:46:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/mggraph-azuread-part1/</guid><description>Best practices using the Microsoft Graph PowerShell SDK to for AzureAD automation, part 1.</description></item><item><title>Midnight Commander meets Windows Terminal</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/mc-meets-terminal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 14:44:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/mc-meets-terminal/</guid><description>Install and add Midnight Commander (MC) to Windows Terminal.</description></item><item><title>Bring Your Own Tenant (updated)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/bring-your-own-tenant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 10:38:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/bring-your-own-tenant/</guid><description>It works in my tenant.</description></item><item><title>Windows Admin Center - 0x80070643</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/windows-server-admin-center-0x80070643/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 18:19:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/windows-server-admin-center-0x80070643/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re facing Windows Admin Center 2009 - Error 0x80070643 on your machine, which might be a domain controller, I&amp;rsquo;ve some bad news for you.</description></item><item><title>Hyper-V, Windows 10, PowerShell</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/hyper-v-windows-10-powershell/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 22:33:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/hyper-v-windows-10-powershell/</guid><description>Add-LocalGroupMember -Group &amp;ldquo;Hyper-V Administrators&amp;rdquo; -Member &amp;ldquo;$(whoami)&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Find PowerShell scripts easier</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/find-powershell-scripts-easier/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 18:08:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/find-powershell-scripts-easier/</guid><description>Windows can index your PowerShell scripts and make them discoverable more easily using search</description></item><item><title>Windows Defender on Windows Server 2019</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/defender-on-windows-server-2019/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 15:32:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/defender-on-windows-server-2019/</guid><description>Error message: You&amp;rsquo;ll need a new app to open this windowsdefender</description></item><item><title>How to manage Hyper-V Administrators on Azure AD joined machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/manage-local-groups-on-azure-ad-joined-machines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 10:29:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/manage-local-groups-on-azure-ad-joined-machines/</guid><description>Get-VM : You do not have the required permission to complete this task. Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that using Add-LocalGroupMember on our Azure AD joined device.</description></item><item><title>Install Azure CLI on Pengwin inside WSL2</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/install-azure-cli-on-pengwin-inside-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 06:32:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/install-azure-cli-on-pengwin-inside-wsl2/</guid><description>Steps to install Azure CLI on Pengwin inside WSL2</description></item><item><title>Admin Guide for your Free Microsoft Teams Subscription (Updated)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-admin-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-admin-guide/</guid><description>Microsoft Teams - The Admin&amp;rsquo;s Check List What do you want to do is to make sure that you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the following checklist:
You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to create additional Global Admin accounts. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to turn on the Multi-Factor Authentication for the Admin accounts. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to change the default technical contact to a distribution group. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to update the Privacy Contact information. You&amp;rsquo;re highly encouraged to turn on the Auditing.</description></item><item><title>PowerShell vs a really huge JSON file</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/powershell-vs-large-json-file/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 21:44:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/powershell-vs-large-json-file/</guid><description>How to process a large json file and get its content out with PowerShell</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security &amp; Responsibility</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 06:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</guid><description>After seeing that some of us - if not most of us - is still able to mess up the configuration of the cloud hosted resources and therefor open up the possibility of some information disclosures, I thought that we need an updated diagram about our responsibilities.
Updated Cloud Security Responsibility Model
The yellow items are my addition, and they show where most of the challenges are located. For a &amp;ldquo;capability team&amp;rdquo; which never had to deal with virtual networks and access management of the resources before the cloud era, I believe these are the parts of the cloud where most of the learning is needed, and could have an epic failure.</description></item><item><title>Practical guide to manage the PAW machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:22:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</guid><description>Where we are We already have some quality materials - like the Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architecture - about the security best practices of the Azure Cloud including possibly everything related to Cybersecurity but I feel that something is missing and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why in a moment. If you take a closer look at the reference material you&amp;rsquo;ll see a red bar titled: Privileged Admin Workstations (PAWs) and in the right side of that bar you&amp;rsquo;ll see ESAE Admin Forest which is described here ESAE Administrative Forest Design Approach</description></item><item><title>Running Azure AD Pro Tip #1</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/azops-pro-tip-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/azops-pro-tip-1/</guid><description>Set up your system in a way which will allow you to receive incoming emails.
Use case #1: Invitations Your users might be invited into a different Tenant to access resources. To accept these invitations - which will arrive in email form - you&amp;rsquo;ve to receive these invitation emails.
Azure AD - New guest user
Use case #2: Official communications You might get into a situation where you want to purchase one or more HTTPS certificates to run your services with your own domain name and not just with the standard https://something.</description></item><item><title>MSDN blogs are back (UPDATED)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/msdn-blogs-are-gone/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 06:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/msdn-blogs-are-gone/</guid><description>Microsoft has started to delete the blogs from MSDN. [UPDATE] 4/17/2019: Microsoft has restored the previously deactivated blogs. I suggest to save everything you find useful into OneNote and keep them forever!
Note from Twitter
ZDNET wrote an article about the planned clean-up the back in November of 2018: https://www.zdnet.com/article/as-microsoft-moves-more-blogs-off-its-msdn-and-technet-sites-heres-how-to-stay-current/
But oddly this act was a surprise to some current and former MSFT employees: Why was my MSDN blog deleted?</description></item><item><title>Red Team type of Access to Azure from Anywhere</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</guid><description>! Warning ! The content of this post might not be aligned with you company&amp;rsquo;s internal IT security rules, I suggest to talk to your manager and request an approval before you try this out in any of your environments.
Introduction, setting the stage We should start with an overall picture of an imaginary Enterprise network
Imagine that your ADFS is sitting behind the corporate firewall and your users cannot access it from the Internet without VPN.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Azure Compliance Manager</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</guid><description>As you probably know Microsoft has a Service Trust Portal from where you can get the #Compliance related information for all Microsoft cloud cervices.
You can even download the Security and Compliance Blueprints
Compliance Manager One of the most helpful offering of the Service Trust Portal is the Compliance Manager, a workflow-based risk assessment tool in which you can get a good overview of your Compliance score which will reflect on how Microsoft understood the different regulations/certifications and the controls required to meet the requirements of these.</description></item><item><title>Show ♥ with PowerShell</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/ps-prompt-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 22:38:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/ps-prompt-1/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m using a custom prompt within PowerShell to save space inside a console and place the current folder&amp;rsquo;s path into the Title bar.
function Prompt { $host.ui.RawUI.WindowTitle = $(Get-Location) Write-Host &amp;#34;PS &amp;#34; -NoNewLine Write-Host $([char]9829) -ForegroundColor Red -NoNewLine &amp;#34; &amp;gt; &amp;#34; } prompt-demo</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2019 and Distributed Cache failure</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-distributed-cache/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-distributed-cache/</guid><description>In some rare cases, right after the creation of a SharePoint 2019 farm, the Distributed Cache service could crash producing:
.NET Runtime Error with Event Id 1026 Application Error with Event Id 1000 And none of the other solutions are able to fix the service. In this case try to:
stop the cache cluster export the cache cluster settings edit the settings by changing the partition count import the settings start and stop the service again revert back the configuration and start the cluster with following scripts:</description></item><item><title>How do I vet the third party applications</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 20:08:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/vet-the-apps/</guid><description>There are lots of third party software vendors focusing on applications and services to extend the functionality of Office 365. There is even a marketplace called AppSource where you can shop from these apps and services.
There are hundreds of applications in each category from where you just have to pick those you like and add them to Office 365 but bare in mind that these apps will ask for permissions in the same way how apps are asking for permissions on your mobile device.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2019 Feature IDs</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-feature-ids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-feature-ids/</guid><description>When I work with SharePoint Server sometimes I need to validate if a FeatureID inside an error message is an Out of the Box ID in the current SharePoint version or it&amp;rsquo;s a custom one created by a Developer.
So I just grab the FeatureID and Google it. And this is the point where this post will come handy for me and hopefully for you as well in the future.</description></item><item><title>Adding Users to Local Groups</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/adding-users-to-local-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/adding-users-to-local-groups/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with the new SharePoint Server 2019 in the last couple of days and after I joined my new VM to the Domain I needed to add my SP_SETUP account to the local Administrators group but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to log in with my Domain Admin to the server.
In the past we had to use the [ADSI] type accelerator to add a local or domain user to a Local Group.</description></item><item><title>My favorite VSCode Extensions (updated)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/my-favorite-vscode-extensions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 11:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/my-favorite-vscode-extensions/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m using Visual Studio Code as my #1 editor for my #PowerShell scripts and modules and these are my favorite extensions what I use every day.
[Note] Keep this list accessible to make my life easier in case I have to install these from scratch :)
Mandatory extensions on my machine #####Bracket Pair Colorizer A customizable extension for colorizing matching brackets
#####C# C# for Visual Studio Code (powered by OmniSharp).</description></item><item><title>Free Microsoft Teams and what's behind</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-and-whats-behind/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 06:44:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/free-microsoft-teams-and-whats-behind/</guid><description>Microsoft Teams is here - for Free The offering was designed to small business and groups of co-workers that don’t have commercial Office 365 subscriptions. You can read the official announcement on the Microsoft Teams Blog
How to get it? Using the http://office.com/teams link, you will be redirected to the right page where you can sign-up for the free service. You can even use your existing Microsoft Account (MSA for sort) to register.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server Core</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-core/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-core/</guid><description>!IMPORTANT! This is not supported by Microsoft. Never do this in your production system.
Now, after we&amp;rsquo;re ready with the disclaimer, let the fun begin.
I always liked the idea of the Windows Server&amp;rsquo;s Core Edition. Who needs the GUI, right?
And I was always disappointed when Microsoft hasn&amp;rsquo;t announced the support of Windows Server Core for SharePoint Server.
I was planning to play with this scenario for years but I never took the time to actually try it out.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2013 - May 2018 CU</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2013-may-2018-cu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2013-may-2018-cu/</guid><description>After installing the May 2018 CU on my SharePoint Server 2013 Developer box I was expecting to see the official Build Number 15.0.5031.1001 but I got something else as a result: Build Version with PowerShell
Weird. 15.0.5023.1000 is the Build Number of the April 2018 CU.
I was thinking
Have I installed the correct CU? I did, it was the ubersrv2013-kb4018397-fullfile-x64-glb.exe Lets check the Central Admin The same version number: Build Version on the Central Admin</description></item><item><title>Whiteboard PowerShell</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/whiteboard-powershell/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 20:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/whiteboard-powershell/</guid><description>People leave the organization. They might retire or look for bigger challenges. Either way as an Office 365 Administrator you have to deal with the situation.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy with SharePoint or with Exchange because they are older services, well documented and you probably have experience with them. So you know how to change ownership of a Site Collection or a Mailbox.
But that is not the case with the Whiteboard Service.</description></item><item><title>Changes to your Azure Information Protection configuration</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/changes-to-your-azure-information-protection-configuration/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 18:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/changes-to-your-azure-information-protection-configuration/</guid><description>Plan for change
We are making some changes to your Azure Information Protection (AIP) configuration. Starting July 1, 2018, we will be enabling the protection features in Azure Information Protection to customers with the eligible Office 365 licenses.
During the fall of 2017 MSFT announced some features for Microsoft 365 to help their customers to meet the requirements of GDPR.
The original announcement is located here: New Microsoft 365 features to accelerate GDPR compliance and this post is about this small part of the announcement:</description></item><item><title>Office365-CLI in a Nano Server Container</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/office365-cli-in-a-nano-server-container/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 21:23:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/office365-cli-in-a-nano-server-container/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m in general interested in everything OfficeDevPnP but I&amp;rsquo;m not a developer. I like to think that I&amp;rsquo;m a Hacker, the old school &amp;ldquo;do something which wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed&amp;rdquo; type of hacker.
These days I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with Docker and I wanted to play with the Office365-CLI and I thought why not run it from a Docker container. And maybe, just to make it more interesting run it from a Nano Server.</description></item><item><title>Learn Offline (during travel)</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/learn-offline-during-travel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 20:21:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/learn-offline-during-travel/</guid><description>If you want to get the most out of your time during travelling, on a train, on an airplane or just on public transportation - if you live in a city where this is an option - I suggest the use Pluralsight&amp;rsquo;s desktop and mobile clients for the experience of offline usage.
You can find the applications download links here https://www.pluralsight.com/downloads</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 21:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/about/</guid><description>My name is David Sass and this is my professional blog.
I spent the all my career around Microsoft technologies, mostly with SharePoint Server. I was a one man Stable team for a couple of years. - Why? Because the Hungarian companies sometimes like to put everything on one man especially when there is not enough IT Professional on the market.
During those years I managed to meet all kinds of challenges in the SharePoint space - we all know the developers and the crazy expectations of the project managers, right?</description></item><item><title>3 months free Pluralsight</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/free-pluralsight-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 19:27:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/free-pluralsight-2/</guid><description>Pluralsight benefits
As you might all know. Microsoft has a program to help the developers to kick-start their Cloud journey. This program is called Visual Studio Dev Essentials.
With this program you can have access to some really useful resources. Let me give you some examples:
Free Azure account + $200 for the first month Access to couple of free Azure services 3 months of free access to Pluralsight MSDN magazine - Digital edition 3 months of LinkedIn Learning access for free It&amp;rsquo;s highly encouraged to register and activate these learning benefits.</description></item></channel></rss>