<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Azure on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in Azure on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 06:32:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Azure CLI on Pengwin inside WSL2</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/install-azure-cli-on-pengwin-inside-wsl2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 06:32:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/install-azure-cli-on-pengwin-inside-wsl2/</guid><description>Steps to install Azure CLI on Pengwin inside WSL2</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security &amp; Responsibility</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 06:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/cloud-security-model/</guid><description>After seeing that some of us - if not most of us - is still able to mess up the configuration of the cloud hosted resources and therefor open up the possibility of some information disclosures, I thought that we need an updated diagram about our responsibilities.
Updated Cloud Security Responsibility Model
The yellow items are my addition, and they show where most of the challenges are located. For a &amp;ldquo;capability team&amp;rdquo; which never had to deal with virtual networks and access management of the resources before the cloud era, I believe these are the parts of the cloud where most of the learning is needed, and could have an epic failure.</description></item><item><title>Practical guide to manage the PAW machines</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 14:22:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/paw-practical-guide/</guid><description>Where we are We already have some quality materials - like the Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architecture - about the security best practices of the Azure Cloud including possibly everything related to Cybersecurity but I feel that something is missing and I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you why in a moment. If you take a closer look at the reference material you&amp;rsquo;ll see a red bar titled: Privileged Admin Workstations (PAWs) and in the right side of that bar you&amp;rsquo;ll see ESAE Admin Forest which is described here ESAE Administrative Forest Design Approach</description></item><item><title>Running Azure AD Pro Tip #1</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/azops-pro-tip-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/azops-pro-tip-1/</guid><description>Set up your system in a way which will allow you to receive incoming emails.
Use case #1: Invitations Your users might be invited into a different Tenant to access resources. To accept these invitations - which will arrive in email form - you&amp;rsquo;ve to receive these invitation emails.
Azure AD - New guest user
Use case #2: Official communications You might get into a situation where you want to purchase one or more HTTPS certificates to run your services with your own domain name and not just with the standard https://something.</description></item><item><title>Red Team type of Access to Azure from Anywhere</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/access-to-azure-from-anywhere/</guid><description>! Warning ! The content of this post might not be aligned with you company&amp;rsquo;s internal IT security rules, I suggest to talk to your manager and request an approval before you try this out in any of your environments.
Introduction, setting the stage We should start with an overall picture of an imaginary Enterprise network
Imagine that your ADFS is sitting behind the corporate firewall and your users cannot access it from the Internet without VPN.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Azure Compliance Manager</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 22:24:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/msft-compliance-manager/</guid><description>As you probably know Microsoft has a Service Trust Portal from where you can get the #Compliance related information for all Microsoft cloud cervices.
You can even download the Security and Compliance Blueprints
Compliance Manager One of the most helpful offering of the Service Trust Portal is the Compliance Manager, a workflow-based risk assessment tool in which you can get a good overview of your Compliance score which will reflect on how Microsoft understood the different regulations/certifications and the controls required to meet the requirements of these.</description></item></channel></rss>