<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SharePoint on kolislab</title><link>http://kolislab.com/tags/sharepoint/</link><description>Recent content in SharePoint on kolislab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:57:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kolislab.com/tags/sharepoint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition Preview</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-se-preview-features/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 06:57:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-se-preview-features/</guid><description>SharePoint Server Subscription Edition Preview, list of features, and feature IDs.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server új napra ébredt</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/hun-sharepoint-server-se/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 18:05:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/hun-sharepoint-server-se/</guid><description>Itt az új SharePoint Server Subscription Edition előzetes kiadása</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2019 and Distributed Cache failure</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-distributed-cache/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 18:13:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-distributed-cache/</guid><description>In some rare cases, right after the creation of a SharePoint 2019 farm, the Distributed Cache service could crash producing:
.NET Runtime Error with Event Id 1026 Application Error with Event Id 1000 And none of the other solutions are able to fix the service. In this case try to:
stop the cache cluster export the cache cluster settings edit the settings by changing the partition count import the settings start and stop the service again revert back the configuration and start the cluster with following scripts:</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2019 Feature IDs</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-feature-ids/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2019-feature-ids/</guid><description>When I work with SharePoint Server sometimes I need to validate if a FeatureID inside an error message is an Out of the Box ID in the current SharePoint version or it&amp;rsquo;s a custom one created by a Developer.
So I just grab the FeatureID and Google it. And this is the point where this post will come handy for me and hopefully for you as well in the future.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint Server Core</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-core/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 11:06:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-server-core/</guid><description>!IMPORTANT! This is not supported by Microsoft. Never do this in your production system.
Now, after we&amp;rsquo;re ready with the disclaimer, let the fun begin.
I always liked the idea of the Windows Server&amp;rsquo;s Core Edition. Who needs the GUI, right?
And I was always disappointed when Microsoft hasn&amp;rsquo;t announced the support of Windows Server Core for SharePoint Server.
I was planning to play with this scenario for years but I never took the time to actually try it out.</description></item><item><title>SharePoint 2013 - May 2018 CU</title><link>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2013-may-2018-cu/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:33:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://kolislab.com/post/sharepoint-2013-may-2018-cu/</guid><description>After installing the May 2018 CU on my SharePoint Server 2013 Developer box I was expecting to see the official Build Number 15.0.5031.1001 but I got something else as a result: Weird. 15.0.5023.1000 is the Build Number of the April 2018 CU.
I was thinking
Have I installed the correct CU? I did, it was the ubersrv2013-kb4018397-fullfile-x64-glb.exe Lets check the Central Admin The same version number: OK. I have seen some weird stuff with SharePoint during these last years.</description></item></channel></rss>